(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T00:55:24.575998",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Dear Novellites,
I'm sorry to have left suddenly.
Trust me, I didn't want to.
But, hopefully, I'll be back soon.
If I'm not, though, then you deserve to know what happened.
Remember when I mentioned those unsettling dreams I've been getting?
I'm just in this courtyard,
but everything feels off when I'm there.
Like...
imagine if you lived your whole life underwater...
and then one day, you were on the surface.
There's something alien about that place,
and when Dreamia is there,
I'm filled with a sense of being...
trapped.
It builds and...
Ah, well, lately, I keep ending up in that courtyard every time I dream,
which has made it hard for me to fall asleep.
I was hoping the dreams would fade so I can continue with my normal routine.
I was hoping the dreams would fade so I could continue with my normal routine.
But since then, they've only grown in intensity.
Finally, I just couldn't take it anymore.
I'd seen that distant castle in my dreams enough times to be able to write a detailed description of it.
Once I did some research, I found a place just like it in the real world, so I'd have to go there.
It might seem crazy, but there's something in the corner of my mind that's pulling me towards it.
And I think if I do it, the dreams will finally stop.
Sorry, guys, for not telling you how bad things had gotten.
The truth is, it wasn't something I wanted to deal with.
I wanted our time together to be fun and full of smiles,
tangents, multiple tangents, nonstop tangents,
and this just kept getting in the way.
So, I'm going to take care of it, and then go back to my happy sugar life. So, yeah, see you soon.
[Present Day]
Well...
this is the place.
Come on, Shiori, get this over with, then he can go back to them.
Come on, Shiori, get this over with, then you can go back to them.
Here goes nothing.
What is this place?
Ah, what?
Hey, you get back here.
It's just gone now, I guess.
This is a nice place.
I was expecting something scary.
It's not too bad, then again, I hate the sun.
Got some pretty flowers over there.
Some pretty butterflies.
I wonder who takes care of these, though.
Someone has to be a gardener here, right?
You got a big giant castle, nice.
Wow.
I wonder if that place is inhabited.
Hmm, if not, I'm gonna take that place.
I feel a lot more complete, too, thinking about it.
A little bit more fluid in my motion.
Ah, thankfully, no one's here to see this.
Huh? For some reason, my heart feels funny.
It's acting weird.
Not sure why.
Oh.
I think... not crap.
I think... I think I'm breaking down!
You are blind, have no blood, just consume, soon, soon, soon,
You don't know about me, you, you, you...
あたし蛾だと知りゃ 皆嫌うが あの蝶と何が違う?
If they knew I was a moth, everyone would hate me, so what makes me different from that butterfly?
あたし蛾だと知らず 皆ガサツに繭を開く
Not knowing I'm a moth, everyone carelessly opens the cocoon.
頭ちゃんぽらんしゅっ たぐぶらんぶらん
Empty-headed, antennae swaying,
宵のまにまに 節足絡み合い
In the depth of twilight, arthropods intertwine.
蝶々のブランド ブランド 闇雲喰らう 喰らう
The brand name of butterflies, mindlessly devouring, devouring.
飛んで火に入った数の自慢ばっか
Just bragging about the number of moths rushing into the fire.
きれいな翅だけを欲しがってる
Desiring only beautiful wings.
撒き散らすscaleは見えない
Unable to see the scattering scales.
You are blind, have no blood, just consume, soon, soon, soon,
You don't know about me, you, you, you...
WOW WOW...
あたしどうせ自分 自分 自分 まみれ
I'm covered in myself anyway.
昆虫の身分 差分 ぶらんぶらん燃えろめ
Insect status, differences, burning up.
「あなた蛾なの? 頑張ってね」ライライ
"If they knew I was a moth, everyone would hate me."
だけど蛾のくせに ハッピーそうで快快
Yet acting happy like a moth, delightful.
切り抜き動画で他を思い感動して動画回して自己陶酔少し点
Getting emotional over clips of others and getting self-absorbed.
正義の瞬間 だけしかいらんらん
Needing only the moment of justice.
親愛の涙にとかしたバイバイ
Dissolved in affectionate tears, bye-bye.
だってペインペイン やなちがうベイベイ
Because pain pain, different bay bay.
生々しさは綺麗にさっぱりパーリーナイト
Rawness nicely cleaned up for a party night.
きれいな翅だけを欲しがってる
Desiring only beautiful wings.
実際は違っても美談
Even if reality is different, it's a touching story.
You are blind, have no blood, just consume, soon, soon, soon,
You don't know about me, you, you, you...
WOW WOW...
偏見さ 過度の嫌い 過度の美化いっそ舐め
Prejudice, excessive hatred, excessive idealization, just lick it.
昆虫の身分 差分 ブルト名
Insect status, differences, brand name.
(ちょう ちょう ちょう ちょう 息の根とまれ) Why don't you wanna be a moth?
Why don't you wanna be a moth?
Don't you wanna be a moth?
モスの嫌子
Moth hater.
you are blind, have no blood
just consume, soon, soon
you don't know about me
you you you...
モスは嫌？
Don't you wanna be a moth?
Where am I?
Hello?
Anyone here?
Really, just me...
in this Halloween-looking town.
Feel a lot different though.
Feeling a little bit more more powerful, actually.
Mhm. Even my eyes are glowing,
a lot more brighter than usual.
Oh, look at my shoes.
Can stomp a little bit better now too.
And my skirt... I feel like it has a lot more bounce to it.
I'm feeling great.
What is this place?
There's eyeflowers around here.
You guys look a lot like my novellas, huh?
My little inky babies.
What else is around here?
There's a bookshelf over there.
I guess if I'm hungry I can eat something here.
Let's see, what do you have?
Eanie, meenie, miny, mo. Maybe I'll eat you later.
Oh, a wonderful, glorious castle over there. It's quite pretty.
And a round, spectacular moon... maybe it's the end of the world here? Who knows? Suki ka kirei.
I'm not sure what I'm doing here though. I feel like there's something missing.
What's this?
Shiori Novella walked towards the table and examines the weird clues in it.
Reeza, are you stalking me again?
Hiya, darling. Don't mind me, I'm just narrating for you.
What do you mean by narrating, huh?
It's this new side hustle we all got.
We? The pay is really good.
Yeah! Can you do something, please?
You know, so that we can narrate it? Yeah, pretty please?
We're getting paid by the word, you know. We have some cute quotes you can read too if you want to hear them.
Yeah, why don't I read you one now? This one says...
Shiori seems concerned that she can't silence the voices in her head.
Oh, sorry Shiori, are we being too loud?
Yeah, there's this thing called a mute button. I would like you to use it.
But you'll definitely might be going a little loopy, huh?
Oh, I wonder if Shiori's mind created us to protect itself.
Wait, but if we're made up, will we still get paid?
Aw, you guys only care about that?
Don't worry so much about it! Real or fake, we're your friends and we're going to help you through this. And we're not the only ones.
Oh, what's that supposed to mean?
Is there anyone else here?
You guys! You can't...
Hey! Get off the floor! No, don't crop over here!
I can't believe it. No, hey! Nyakat!
I can't believe you guys are here. You're supposed to make this a happy occasion, but I can't believe you started flopping on my floor!
What are you guys doing here, though? Salt and pepper?
Shiori followed the nyakuzas towards the bookshelf. Books had always been her source of comfort during hard times, so returning to them now felt natural to her.
Hey, are there any fanfictions you're oshi in there?
Of course there are.
This is Shiori's bookshelf after all.
Oh, hey, that reminds me of this great manga I read the other day about...
Hey, back to the topic, you guys.
By the way, who is your oshi, Shiori? It's me, right? Me? What a funny joke!
Uh, you know, ever since we started narrating for you, I've had this odd urge to tangent.
I think it's the magic of this realm. We're all slowly becoming Shioris.
Yeah, how about let's not do that, huh?
Uh, it means we better help you out quickly. I don't think the internet is ready for your bi-weekly rule.
Hey, I'm wholesome, though! I'm a wholesome, halloweened girl!
can already feel the intrusive thoughts creeping up on me.
I can already feel the intrusive thoughts creeping up on me.
Resist, beboop.
Uh say, Shiori, I think the Nyakuzas want to tell you something.
Say, Shiori, I think the Nyakuzas want to tell you something.
What is it?
You guys are pointing at something.
Oh, the Nyakuzas are saying that the books are full of pages
trapped away in your mind.
If you unlock what's within,
you'll be able to go back home. So go on, take a book.
Already on it.
How about this little one?
Ooh! Shiori grabbed one of
the most powerful books out there.
It contains vast wisdoms about humanity.
But to unlock it, you have to go under
a great and difficult trial.
Was she sure that she was ready?
What kind of trial is this, huh?
Okay, Shiori, for this book,
I want you to act out some memes,
or maybe some poses for me.
Come on, even, you know,
just two would work.
That's what I think of your memes, so...
I changed my mind, Shiori.
I want you to do three. Yeah, three.
Three? All right.
Just for you, but you have to be specific.
What do you want me to do?
Hmm, for the first one,
maybe you could unleash
your patented Shiori beam.
My Shiori beam?
Ah, fine, just for you.
Okay.
The... Shiori...
Beam!
Oh. Oh, um, uh, ah.
That was—that was pretty close.
I can, can you do it again?
Can you do it again?
Uh, maybe this time,
shout something like cool,
shout something cool,
like, 'Explosion!'
I think you're expecting too much from me.
How about we do something else?
Uh, okay, fine.
Ugh, okay, fine.
Hmm. Oh, I know,
for the next one,
you have a lot of people watching, right?
I want you to rizz up the audience.
Yeah.
Can you like, cavort on the camera?
And then, and then give us your best line.
Yeah, do that.
Is this like your secret fantasy, bebs?
Uhh, no, just—just do it.
Just do it. I'm in charge here, okay?
Ah, that's what you want, huh?
But tonight,
I'm using you.
Shiori!
Why?
What?
Ah.
Are you okay there, my girl?
Yeah, yeah. All good.
You guys are supposed to be rizzing the rizzah.
You're supposed to be rizzing everybody else.
But she's always rizz'd, though.
I'm—I'm sure everybody
is blushing now, right?
That sounds pretty good.
I don't know.
Oh well, okay,
I have a third one for you.
Are you ready?
Sure, just for you.
Okay, for this last one,
I want you to pretend
that the darkness is consuming you
and you're in danger,
and the only thing that will save your life
is if you hit the biggest dab ever.
Uhh, the things I do for love.
Okay. How's this?
Dab!
Shiori!
Wow, that was weak.
That's not fighting for your life.
That's like you're bored.
Okay, do it again.
But this time, power, energy,
powerful dab.
Yes.
Okay. Gotta get on my trauma here.
Okay. Dab!
Ooh! Okay, Shiori,
that was pretty good.
Now, can you like dab back and forth
like 10 times over and over
and over again?
Okay, I think that's expecting
too much, though.
I think that's enough memes
for you, bebs.
Through her efforts,
Shiori gained two apples
that contain magical powers
from all of her cringe.
Oh, I can make the apples kiss.
All right, now that I have these sketchy items,
I'm a head out of here.
All right.
Where do I put these apples?
That's not how it works, Shiori.
You're trying to jump ahead,
but you got to do the trials in order.
Uhh, all right.
What do?
You need to do all the dabs, okay?
Come on. I'll help you
unlock the pink book. Got it.
Oh, fine, fine. The Nyakuzas want to help.
All right, pink book, let's see.
This one.
Nyakuza?
Uh, they say that that's the book of playtime.
That's my favorite.
All I have to do is juggle the apple.
If you say so.
You know, uh, juggling hasn't worked for me in the past.
Oh, um, let me check what the script says, then.
You have a script?
Well, then do this.
Please, everyone is having fun, so uh,
even if you don't do it right, it's still good enough.
Huh?
Woah, if you're okay with good enough...
...it's good enough for me.
All right. Do your best.
I'll try.
All right, let's go.
Oh.
Ah.
Ah, it's not too bad.
Oh.
Ah.
Spinning and juggling.
Yeah.
You like that? You're getting entertained, aren't you?
Do your best.
Yeah.
Are you sure you weren't born to do this?
Oh, you think you was born to be a clown?
Nothing, you're a clown. You're Shiori.
Oh, so have fun enough for you now, huh?
How many once when you do this work?
It's good enough, huh?
Oh, my luck ran out.
Oh, all right.
Let's see what we got.
Huh?
It looks like you're getting a pot, huh? 'Cause uh...
If there's an RPG section on the trials, then maybe you can use that pot as your helm.
It does come with a plus three to magic.
Huh?
Oh.
Where does it say that, Bejoux?
Where does it say that, Bijou?
Shiori.
Is Shiori definitely equipped it then, huh?
He just want me to look stupid.
Not like that, you know.
This way you'll be ready just in case there's a boss fight.
Fine.
I'm only doing this because of love.
Like this?
Shiori, uh, apparently puts the cauldron on her head, it grants her the power of...
I don't know, mild neck pain, probably.
Shiori, is wearing that helping?
No, but I feel kind of funny.
Uh, maybe she should try another Shiori bean, no, just to be sure.
Come on, Moco-chan, don't tease Shiori.
Come on, Mococo, don't tease Shiori.
The script doesn't say anything about a boss fight or Shiori wearing the cauldron.
Shiori will remember this.
All right, what do I do now?
Then Yakuza say that you can use the cauldron to unlock the Blue Book of Responsibilities.
All you need to do to complete that task is make us an apple pie.
I'm sorry, you want me to make an apple pie with these?
All right.
Now what book is this?
Oh.
Hey, just wondering, but who wrote your script?
Uh, I don't know, I guess it could have been anyone, really.
Anyway, uh, where was I?
Oh, here, after the Yakuza's display of awesome magical abilities,
the likes of which no other creatures could ever dream of attaining, Shiori took the greatest spoon ever crafted and used it to stir the apples.
The spoon, why is it so big?
Hey, I could probably bonk you guys with this.
Uh, no bonking, please.
Oh, fine, I'll just use it for spoon things, just like that. All right, think this will actually make apple pie?
Looks good.
All right, let's see what's inside, then.
Oh.
Shiori takes the apple pie.
Meanwhile, a friend, who may or may not be imaginary, but were definitely very hungry, look at the pie with anticipation.
Can you do us a favor and leave the pie on the table so we can imagine eating it?
Ah, my hungry puppies, I don't think you're allowed to eat apple pie, though.
Please, please eat. I know it was really hard work.
We'll see, we'll see.
All right.
Now that we have that apple pie,
What now?
Shiori put the pie on the table.
Then she thought it would be nice to pour tofu milk for her friends too.
I don't have tofu milk!
Are you...
Are you sure?
I'm very sure that I don't have tofu milk.
Uh, maybe we could just pretend?
All right. That's a good idea.
Gulp, gulp, gulp, gulp...
It turns out imaginary milk is pretty good.
Oh, give it here. I want it for my imaginary coffee.
I'll trade you for a slice of the apple pie.
Deal! Shiori, can you give Mococo some pie?
How am I going to give my imaginary friends my imaginary pie?
But you know what? I think a better question would be...
What do I do with this?
Whoa! Cool! Wow!
Oh, cool. Maybe you're supposed to wield it as your sword, like this?
It does come with a plus-three to attack.
Seriously, where are you seeing these numbers?
Mococo-chan, why would a microphone be your weapon?
Huh? I don't know, but if she's on an adventure, she's going to need a sword, okay?
Yeah! But she's not an adventurer in the script.
Well, maybe I want to add my own parts to this script. Is that really so wrong?
Come on, she wants to go home. Don't worry, Shiori, I can help you with that.
Why don't you go back to the bookshelf? At least one person's useful here.
Don't worry, Shiori. This is almost over, I promise.
But first, you need to unlock the Book of Memories.
Do you remember ever getting lulled to sleep by a lullaby when you were a child?
Of course not, I had no childhood.
Well, to unlock the powers of the final book, you need to take the microphone and sing the yakuza to sleep. You got this, okay?
All right, I'll do my best.
いつもどう頑張って努力をしたところで
No matter how hard I try or how much effort I put in,
指示示されるのは平均値
the results are always average.
やってられないよ
I can't go on like this,
くだらない評価に踊らされてばかり
constantly being manipulated by useless measures of worth.
もう嫌になっちゃったこの人生
I've already come to hate this life,
なら生まれ変わろうか
so, I think I'll restart my life.
「異常」「異常」が胸を埋め尽くして
My chest is completely filled with "abnormality",
普通じゃない自分になるの
I'm becoming a me that isn't normal.
自問自答繰り返して手に入れたの
I ask myself over and over, "Did I get it?"
新しいワタシを
A brand new me.
ほら見てよ　ほら触れてよ
Look at me now, touch me right now,
凡庸な服を捨て去って
I'll throw away my ordinary clothes.
今サナギから　蝶になるの
Now, from my chrysalis, I'll become a butterfly.
ありのまま全て見せつけて
I'll show off everything as it is.
冷めきった舞台　演者はいない
There are no performers on this cooled-off stage,
ならステップ刻んで one, two, three
so I'll beat out the steps, 1, 2, 3.
踊らされるんじゃない　踊るのよ
I'm not being manipulated, I'm dancing!
さぁ　さぁ　さぁ　狂って
Yeah, I'm going crazy!
「普通」「普通」が呪いをかけてきて
"Normality" cast a curse on me,
「異常」「異常」に憧れたの
and I yearned for "abnormality".
異論、持論に興味などないからもう
I don't have any interest in your differing opinions,
鍵をかけて
I've already locked the door.
「好き」「嫌い」を疾うに通り越して
I went beyond "love" and "hate",
「異常」に恋焦がれていたの
and fell deeply in love with "abnormality".
歪んだ愛の成れの果て創られた
And from the ruins of that warped love, it was created—
新しいワタシを
a brand new me.
ほら見てよ　ほら触れてよ
Look at me now, touch me right now,
凡庸な服を捨て去って
I'll throw away my ordinary clothes.
今サナギから　蝶になるの
Now, from my chrysalis, I'll become a butterfly.
ありのまま全て見せつけて
I'll show off everything as it is.
冷めきった舞台　演者はいない
There are no performers on this cooled-off stage,
ならステップ刻んで one, two, three
so I'll beat out the steps, 1, 2, 3.
踊らされるんじゃない　踊るのよ
I'm not being manipulated, I'm dancing!
さぁ　さぁ　さぁ　狂って
Yeah, I'm going crazy!
暗い部屋　1人きり
In a dark room by myself,
鏡の前　午前0時
before the mirror at midnight.
「アナタ誰」「ワタシ誰」
"Who are you?" "Who am I?"
問い掛けど返事は無かった
I asked, but received no reply.
狂え
Go crazy.
Go crazy!
ほら見せてよ 新しいワタシを
Look at me now, the brand new me,
ほら見てよ ほら触れてよ
Look at me now, touch me right now,
透明な服で着飾って
Dressed up in transparent clothes,
今サナギから 蝶になるの
Now from my chrysalis, I'll become a butterfly,
ありのまま全て見せつけて
Showing off everything as it is,
熱狂の舞台 演者はいない
On this impassioned stage, there are no performers,
ならステップ刻んで one two three
So I'll beat out the steps, 1, 2, 3,
踊らされるんじゃない 踊るのよ
I'm not being manipulated, I'm dancing!
さあ さあ さあ 狂って 「異常」が胸を埋めつくして
Go crazy! "Abnormality" fills my chest,
普通じゃない自分になるの
Becoming a me that isn't normal,
歪んだ愛の成れの果て創られた 叶わぬ恋
An unfulfillable love born from warped love,
「異常」が胸を埋めつくして 普通じゃない自分になるの
"Abnormality" fills my chest, becoming a me that isn't normal,
自問自答繰り返し手に入れた 新しいワタシを
The brand new me I finally obtained after soul-searching.
That wasn't a lullaby.
If anything, everything was perfectly ready. It was started.
If anything, everything was already ready. It had started.
What do you mean? I fall asleep to that song all the time.
Oh, it looks like it worked, anyway.
You got the last item! A nice... the beautiful purple heart.
But what do I do with this now?
I think the Myagusa are telling you to put the items in their slots on the table.
Ah, I see. Alright, let's put this over here.
And then we got the microphone here.
And then last but not least, we got and here's my cauldron!
Uh, wait, is something supposed to happen now?
I think so. Mogu mogu?
Huh? You didn't see it yet?
No, all the books in your archive have been activated, and you can go home!
Yes! Oh, oh, those books have unlocked the power of our friendship.
With all of us working together, we'll be able to reopen the portal.
We worked together? I think I did everything.
And then Shiori approached the archway, eagerly awaiting the moment when...
the combined strength of all of her friends would cause the portal to reactivate.
Oh, so I can I can go home now, right?
Uh, that that's weird. The power of friendship usually works.
I know, right? Maybe those were all our social links?
Maybe we're really not friends, huh? Maybe she needs to find an item to give her a plus three...
Maybe we're really not friends, huh? Maybe she needs to find an item...
to give her a plus three to the power of friendship.
But what item? I think I used everything.
Mhm. Why not take the cue cards instead?
Oh, let me look them over.
I hope it helps. I don't want to be stuck here. Okay, uh, it it says here that...
no matter how hard Shiori wanted to, she can't move backward.
Uh, sorry, that wasn't very helpful after all.
So what you're telling me is I'm going to be stuck in this Halloween-ish world, right? Yeah.
Don't worry, Shiori, we're still here for you. Uh, maybe there's a silver lining in all of this.
Okay, but I'm talking to a rock, two dogs, and one bird.
Well, when you put it like that, maybe this isn't so great.
But this is just the start of this world. I bet if you keep moving forward,
you'll discover that it's not as scary a place as it looks now.
Yeah, that's true. Plus, you've gained a whole new dimension.
And, yeah, it's different, but it might be good, right?
Yeah, I don't know. I mean, I look great.
But I still like the old me.
You're still the old you too, you know? You just got extra stuff now.
On the next part of your journey.
Yeah, exactly. Huh? Oh.
Ah. But, you know, I wanted my character arc to be done.
Sometimes I like having things stay the way they are.
Is that really all you want? Uh, well, duh.
But if all the pages in your books just are repeated over and over, you know, it gets pretty boring, right?
And even if it didn't, moving forward is how we grow.
Yeah. And how you find new games to play.
Or new friends to make.
And new friends to make.
And how we gained new friends. We would have never met in the first place had we not taken a chance on change.
And your story would be boring without us, right?
I guess. I mean, it's great having you guys as friends and have the novelites to keep me company.
I guess. I mean, it's great having you guys as friends and have the Novellites to keep me company.
But, you know, sometimes I just want to look back, too. And if this is my book, then I should be able to decide what happens, right? I want to go at my own pace.
More books?
What's this?
Oh.
Oh, wow.
Hang on, there's a cute item supposed to be...
Well, hopefully this one's a good one.
Oh.
Okay, well, it says, "Don't worry, Shiori."
"While your powers will continue to grow, and your journey will take you to realities as of yet unblessed to humanity..."
As long as you have my bookmark, you'll be protected.
Please use it as your link to the past and your guide to the future.
Hey, I didn't see that car earlier, and whose bookmark is that? Or where was it?
I don't know! I just looked away and then when I looked back, suddenly it was there in front of me.
But what do I do with this?
I think the Nyakuza want you to put the bookmark in the archway.
Oh. Maybe like... like this?
It worked!
The Nyakuza say that thanks to the bookmark, the portal's been opened permanently. You can go back home, but the 3D world will stay available to you. They want you to know that this reality is so much bigger than just this one place.
There's a lot to see and archive here. And when you're done with this reality, there are even more places for you to explore.
It looks like your character arc is just beginning. But don't worry, whenever you need us, we'll be here to help, Shiori.
All right. Well, yeah. Bye-bye, suckers! Bye, Shiori!
代わりに溺れて
Drown instead of me,
行けないところまで哀しみを弾くだけ
play the sadness to where I cannot go.
跳ねた言葉を踏み締めた音に乗って
Stepping firmly on the bouncing words,
心まで踊りたいの
I want to dance with all my heart.
雨上がり哀しいにおいの街
The city smells of melancholy after the rain,
雲をかきわけたお日様が眠気交じりで溜まった涙を見ている
as the sunshine that parted the clouds sleepily watches the pooled tears.
雨上がり正しい通り道
The right path after the rain,
足元は湿って危ないわ
where your feet are wet and dangerous.
ぬかるみにハマらないよう注意して
Watch out so you don't get stuck in the mud,
お気に入りの靴の身代わりになって
taking the place of my favorite shoes.
あなたの言葉を弾いてみせるよ
I'll play your words for you.
遅れたバスに乗りたくないなら
If you don't want to catch the late bus,
溜まった涙が跳ねる音のリズムに乗っていけ
ride the rhythm of the bouncing tears.
代わりに溺れて
Drown instead of me,
行けないところまで哀しみを弾くだけ
play the sadness to where I cannot go.
跳ねた言葉を踏み締めた音が鳴って
The sound of stepping on the bouncing words rings,
心まで無敵
and even my heart is invincible.
ジャンプ ジャンプなんて出来ない
Jump, jump? I can't do that.
地球にいじわるされて掴まれているの
The earth is being mean and holding me down.
ステップ ステップちょっとむずい
Step, step is a little tricky,
雨の中転ばぬように静かに踊るの
dancing quietly so I don't fall in the rain.
雨上がり水溜まった道
A puddle-filled road after the rain,
どれだけ深く沈んでいける?
how deep can I sink into it?
降ったり止んだり忙しいね
It's busy raining and stopping.
履かなくても大丈夫な人もいるけど
Some people are fine without wearing them,
梅雨の救世主になって
but be the savior of the rainy season!
あなたの言葉で遊んでみせるよ
I'll play with your words.
満員電車は曇ってやばいから
A packed train is gloomy and awful, so
溜まった涙が跳ねる音のリズムに乗ろう
let's ride the rhythm of the bouncing tears.
代わりに溺れて
Drown instead of me,
見えないところまで哀しみを弾くだけ
play the sadness to where I cannot see.
跳ねた言葉を踏み締めた音に乗って
Stepping firmly on the bouncing words,
心まで踊りたい
I want to dance with all my heart.
ジャンプ ジャンプなんて出来ない
Jump, jump? I can't do that.
この先道悪慣れてるあたしに任せて
The road ahead is rough, so leave it to me—I'm used to it.
ステップ ステップちょっとむずい
Step, step is a little tricky,
雨の中汚れないように静かにうたう
singing quietly so I don't get dirty in the rain.
Singing quietly so I don't get dirty in the rain
ジャンプ ジャンプなんて出来ない
Jump, jump, I can't do it at all
地球にいじわるされて掴まれているの
The earth is being mean and holding me down
ステップ ステップちょっとむずい
Step, step, it's a bit tricky
雨の中濡れぬように静かに踊るの
Dancing quietly so I don't get wet in the rain
Give me, give me a few minutes.
Dancing in the rain is pretty fun.
But you know, my boots feel all gross now.
They're covered in water and stuff.
Need to shake the droplets off.
And you know what? My jacket makes me kind of feel gross too.
I think it's time we take it off.
Oh my, wow, what am I showing?
Oh no, my arm, this arm, the other arm!
Oh no, what am I doing?
Oh, it feels a little bit better now.
It's less wet, so, oh.
This place is a lot prettier now.
I can see the stars everywhere.
It's a lot better than being in the other world with the voices in my head.
When you hear nothing but "ooh" and "bow-wow" and "let's rock!"
It gets a little tiring, to be honest.
Ah, it's peaceful.
You even see some beautiful flowers.
They look like they're glowing.
You should give congratulations to whoever the gardener is.
I wonder what kind of flowers these are.
They're blue and pink.
Could be any flower.
I wonder if I can take some.
Oh, and it looks like the castle is, oh, it has a lot of lights there.
Maybe they're having a party?
Still don't know who lives there, well, but if it's empty, it's mine now.
You think I could just barge in there and be like, "Hey yo, it's Shiori!"
Does Wanderin' Ears sorry?
Ah, but you know what? If breaking dimensions isn't enough for you,
well, I think it's time to break your bank.
Let's see what we can break your bank with.
With... Oh, what is this?
Wow! That looks like a handy-dandy belt.
Oh, it looks kind of similar to my belt here, right? Oh, it's over here. Yeah.
So if you struggle with falling pants, or you just don't believe in pants,
you believe they don't cover up that shame well enough,
well, you can get this belt to help with that. Yeah.
It'll put your faith back in humanity by 0.1%.
And if that's not enough for you, well,
if you don't want to wear it, why don't you whip it?
I don't know, I don't care, but it's a belt.
Oh, and now it's time for some passionate Japanese.
ズボンとパンツが好きですか？
Do you like trousers and pants?
私のベルト、パワーなりから、すみません！
My belt has power, so... sorry!
買いたいですか？ベルトベルト欲しいですか？
Want to buy? Do you want a belt?
可愛いなりか、買いたいですか？
Is it cute? Do you want to buy it?
Please buy! Please, お願いします！
Please buy! Please, I'm begging you!
野生ゆるしでおねがいします
Please forgive my wildness!
私のベルト、whip it!
My belt, whip it!
お尻が好きですか？whip whip whip whip!
Do you like butts? Whip whip whip whip!
ああ、パンツ、パンツありますか？
Ah, do you have pants? Pants?
おお、ベルト、ベルト！
Oh, belt, belt!
そして、万歳、乾杯、盆栽、ベタイヤーイ！
And then, banzai, kanpai, bonsai, betaiyarii!
washi no nihongo jozu?
Is my Japanese good?
It better be.
Oh, but besides that, um, minasan arigatou gozaimasu! Novellaits, thank you for watching and helping me not perish!
And kaput!
Thanks to you, I now know to throw away moldy bread and moldy food. Yeah!
I now know that there's soft cheese, and hard cheese, and other types of cheese, and I just really like to point 'cause I'm cheesy.
I now know that there's soft cheese, hard cheese, and other types of cheese, and I just really like to point 'cause I'm cheesy.
But yeah, thank you for watching me, and supporting me, and keeping me company.
But yeah, thank you for watching me, supporting me, and keeping me company.
Sorry, I've been yelling a lot.
Minasan, zenbu de... arigatou gozaimasu!
Everyone, thank you so much for everything!
Minasan wa tottemo kakkoii desu! Ichiban desu!
You all look so cool! You're number one!
But you know, I have one more song for you guys. That's right, the number one!
But you know, I have one more song for you guys. That's right, number one!
So, if you don't mind taking a few more minutes to listen to my cool...
watashi no koe desu...
...my voice...
Please, please listen. Or not, I don't know.
Give me a few seconds, I'm tired...
Okay, here I go.
この空の果てに
At the end of the sky,
昔々、ここによく似た
long, long ago, it looked like this.
命に溢れる 星があったという
It is said that there was a star brimming with life.
人は欲望に溺れ やがて
People drowned in greed, and before long
世界は息をするのをやめた
the world stopped breathing.
長い、長い時が流れ
A long, long time went by,
聞こえたのは あなたが あなたが 私を呼ぶ声
and what I could hear was your, your voice calling me
私は鳥になり 遠く、遠く 羽ばたいて行く
I will become a bird, and go far, far, flapping my wings.
幾千の星を越え あなたの元へ
Beyond thousands of stars and to your side.
体は燃え尽き 灰になって 消えて行って も
Even if my body burns, turns to ash, and disappears
心は時を超え 約束の場所へ 飛ぶ
my heart will cross time and soar to our promised place.
自分の姿も思い出せず
Even if I forget my own appearance,
微かな自我は誰にも見えず
Even if no one can see my faint existence...
永い、永い時が流れ 辿り着いた
A long, long time passes and I have finally arrived
あなたが あなたが 待ち続けた星
You are, you are the star that kept waiting.
君と僕が生まれた地球
The place where you and I were born
ここに同じ名前を付けよう
Let's give it the same name here.
二人の心はひとつになり 光になった
Our hearts became one, became light,
全ての命がまた生まれるように
so that all life will be born again.
同じ過ちをも二度とは犯さないよう
So that we will never commit these same mistakes again
私は愛の歌 ここで歌い続ける
Here, I will continue to sing songs of love.
Thank you for the peaceful, fun memories!
I'm grateful for all your time, kindness, & warmth!
May we all find our happiness down the road!
Let's keep doing our best to be kind & to smile~
#Shiorin3D
3D SHOWCASE